<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<content type="LES"><id>360</id>
<timestamp_x>1162482874</timestamp_x>
<date_create>1153395407</date_create>
<created_by>1837</created_by>
<active>Y</active>
<course_id>10</course_id>
<chapter_id>135</chapter_id>
<name>Folders and pages properties creating</name>
<sort>100</sort>
<preview_picture></preview_picture>
<preview_text></preview_text>
<preview_text_type>text</preview_text_type>
<detail_picture></detail_picture>
<detail_text><![CDATA[<p>To create a new page property open the Site Explorer module settings page: </p>

<p><i>Settings -&gt; System settings -&gt; Module settings -&gt; Site Explorer</i>.</p>

<p>Then find the group of fields <b>Property types</b> (<b>Settings for sites</b> section):</p>

<p><img src="cid:resources/res18/juW6d.0Dgb2.prop_types.png" height="209" width="524"/></p>

<p>In this form, you will find properties types in the form of text strings (title, work_pic etc.) and names (short descriptions) of these types.</p>

<p>The product has several reserved types of properties used by some system functions. Reserved properties include:</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>title</code> &ndash; used to set the additional page title; </li>

  <li><code>adv_desired_target_keywords</code> &ndash; used to set the desirable keywords for the advertisement shows; </li>

  <li><code>not_show_nav_chain</code> &ndash; used to disable the navigational chain (breadcrumb navigation) for page or section. </li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Property types</strong> intended for managing and using properties values in source code. It is strongly recommended to not modify types of <em>reserved</em> properties. They could already be used in the product code.</p>

<p><strong>Propery names</strong> are intended for properties values management through the system visual interface. You can edit the property names, if you want.</p>

<div class="hint">Properties values can be assign through the system visual interface as well as in the source code.</div>

<p>You can create your own page property types by using the empty form fields. For example, you can create a <i>keyword</i> property (the HTML equivalent <code>keywords</code>), a <i>page description property</i> (<code>description</code>), an <i>author property</i> (<code>author</code>). Only the Roman letters are allowed in the property names.</p>

<div class="hint">A set of properties can be assigned individually for one site or for all sites simultaneously. 
  <p><img src="cid:resources/res18/F4Rt4.E8Z1m.prop_types_for_site.png" height="267" width="584"/></p>
</div>
<p></p>

<div class="important"><b>Note!</b> Properties &quot;keywords&quot; and &quot;description&quot; are used as the page metadata. Therefore, their names must be the same as the HTML meta tag attribute values (<code>KEYWORDS</code> and <code>DESCRIPTION</code>).</div>

<p>The trial version contains the <code>work_pic</code> property ("Photo for sections"), which can be used to define a picture to be displayed on a current page, or all pages of a desired section. The image path depends on the site template settings. For example, the template settings may define the path to a folder containing the site images. If so, the <code>work_pic</code> property value can contain only the image file name.</p>
<p>
<table><tr>
<td><img src="cid:resources/res18/ZruLP.P6pDZ.folder_prop.png" height="166" width="335"/></td>
<td>&nbsp</td><td><img src="cid:resources/res18/ngbOU.n2U0Y.sect_pict.png" height="166" width="252"/></td></tr></table></p>
]]></detail_text>
<detail_text_type>html</detail_text_type>
</content>