<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<content type="LES"><id>398</id>
<timestamp_x>1162482875</timestamp_x>
<date_create>1153816754</date_create>
<created_by>1837</created_by>
<active>Y</active>
<course_id>10</course_id>
<chapter_id>148</chapter_id>
<name>How to implement the news display (an example of work with components)</name>
<sort>500</sort>
<preview_picture></preview_picture>
<preview_text></preview_text>
<preview_text_type>text</preview_text_type>
<detail_picture></detail_picture>
<detail_text><![CDATA[
<p>First step in implementing pages for the news display is to create the appropriate information block in the administrative interface and populate it with elements; that is, the news.</p>

<p>When creating a new information block, you have to specify the path to a page with the list of elements of this block (news) and the path to a page with the detailed view of an element (a single news).</p>

<p>The above-mentioned pages must be present in the site structure. For example, <code>/about/news/index.php</code> for the list of news and <code>/about/news/detail.php</code> for the news details.</p>

<p>You can create pages in any way you like: using either the Site Explorer module or WYSIWYG editor.</p>

<p></p>

<p>After you have created a new page, place the required components in it. If you are working with the news list page, drag and drop the <i>News Lis</i>t component from the palette on the page. Drag and drop the <i>News Details</i> component on the page intended to display the news details.</p>

<p>If you wish to arrange the news export to RSS, place a descriptive image in the page (RSS 2.0) and apply a link to it. The link should point to an existing page (e.g. <code>/about/news/rss.php</code>) with the RSS Export component placed in it.
  <br />
</p>

<p><img src="cid:resources/res103/CJoo1.OLjsl.news_list.png" height="233" width="465"/>
  <br />

  <br />
Please note that you should make sure that the RSS export is allowed for the given information block.</p>
]]></detail_text>
<detail_text_type>html</detail_text_type>
</content>