<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<content type="LES"><id>375</id>
<timestamp_x>1162482874</timestamp_x>
<date_create>1153472181</date_create>
<created_by>1837</created_by>
<active>Y</active>
<course_id>10</course_id>
<chapter_id>140</chapter_id>
<name>Metadata</name>
<sort>100</sort>
<preview_picture></preview_picture>
<preview_text></preview_text>
<preview_text_type>text</preview_text_type>
<detail_picture></detail_picture>
<detail_text><![CDATA[<p>The main purpose of the metadata usage is the site optimizing for the search engines. Search engines use metadata for the site documents indexation.</p>

<p>An example of metadata control is the mechanism of assigning keywords and descriptions to pages and sections of a site. By default, the Bitrix Site Manager distributive has these two types of metadata configured. You can extend the list of the available metadata types by implementing the same algorithm. </p>

<p>To manage the metadata values via the system visual interface preliminarily it is necessary to create corresponding page properties (properties can be created on the <b>Site Explorer</b> settings page): </p>

<p><em>Setting -&gt; System settings -&gt; Module settins -&gt; Site Explorer.</em> </p>

<p><img src="cid:resources/res49/ihno0.8J4oq.prop_types.png" height="214" width="499"/></p>

<p></p>

<div class="hint"><strong>Note!</strong> Properties &quot;keywords&quot; and &quot;description&quot; are used as the page metadata. Therefore, their names must be the same as the HTML meta tag attribute values (<code>KEYWORDS</code> and <code>DESCRIPTION</code>).</div>

<p></p>

<div class="hint">A set of properties can be assigned individually for one site or for all sites simultaneously. 
  <p><img src="cid:resources/res49/0KuPa.sTvEr.site_page_prop.png" height="367" width="500"/></p>

More detailed information about properties management is available in the &quot;Properties of pages and folders&quot; section.
</div>
]]></detail_text>
<detail_text_type>html</detail_text_type>
</content>