<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<content type="LES"><id>358</id>
<timestamp_x>1162541754</timestamp_x>
<date_create>1153384514</date_create>
<created_by>1837</created_by>
<active>Y</active>
<course_id>10</course_id>
<chapter_id>133</chapter_id>
<name>Include and editable areas</name>
<sort>400</sort>
<preview_picture></preview_picture>
<preview_text></preview_text>
<preview_text_type>text</preview_text_type>
<detail_picture></detail_picture>
<detail_text><![CDATA[
<p>To provide the visual dynamic control over a modern web site, some design parts are implemented as the editable areas. These areas are used for graphic, textual or any other information publishing. Special system mechanism allows to proceed to these areas editing directly from the public section.</p>

<p>The Bitrix Site Manager supports two forms of editable areas: </p>

<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr valign="top"><td>
        <ul>
          <li><b>Editable areas in site template</b>. Usually it is areas with copyrights, links, contact information and etc. </li>
        </ul>
      </td><td><img src="cid:resources/res6/iSEfY.aQPV6.incl_area_teml.png" height="140" width="272"/></td></tr>
  
    <tr><td>&nbsp;</td><td>&nbsp;</td><td>&nbsp;</td></tr>
  
    <tr valign="top"><td>
        <ul>
          <li><b>Include areas on site pages</b>. These areas are used for displaying references, forms (e.g. authorization or search forms), news or any other static or dynamic information. </li>
        </ul>
      </td><td><img src="cid:resources/res6/h1aNP.rR95s.incl_area_page.png" height="134" width="272"/></td></tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Space for displaying include and editable areas is defined in site template. Templates supplied with demo version of product contains examples of include areas for displaying on one exact page as well as for displaying on all pages of exact site section. </p>

<p>The system allows users to adjust their own conditions according to which includes areas will be shown. To do so a user need to make corresponding modifications in site template. For example, there can be created an include area that will be shown on exact days only.</p>

<p>You can turn on the special mode that enables to view the include areas by clicking the button in the administrative toolbar. As the result all editable areas will be spotlighted as separate blocks. Links allowing to proceed to area editing will be displayed in top right conner of each block. </p>
]]></detail_text>
<detail_text_type>html</detail_text_type>
</content>